{
    "id": "25240654ae164e78b07691a6529fda1b",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Suddenly I ……………………….. a thud.",
            "description": "We hear sounds that come to our ears. To listen to something is to pay attention to it.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "heard",
                "listened",
                "listened to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "87c00cc0c73243cfa41ac5b88a5bfae5"
        },
        {
            "question": "I didn’t ………………………… the knock because  ………………………….. the radio.",
            "description": "We hear sounds that come to our ears. To listen to something is to pay attention to it.",
            "answers": [
                "hear, was listening to",
                "listen to, hearing",
                "hear, listened to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "903905eaa4c24af3a7085e6960b44bba"
        },
        {
            "question": "Please speak a bit louder. I cannot ………………………. you.",
            "description": "We hear sounds that come to our ears. To listen to something is to pay attention to it.",
            "answers": [
                "hear",
                "listen",
                "listen to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "82d89b18c5614d589aa8b3cbf3c30035"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. somebody coming up the stairs.",
            "description": "Hear is not normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "can hear",
                "am hearing",
                "can to hear"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c157156e9e134a358f2ac4f667bc41f7"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. what I am going to say.",
            "description": "If there is an object, listen is used with to.",
            "answers": [
                "Hear carefully",
                "Listen carefully to",
                "Listen carefully"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "88422886055f4ce68217bb16717df085"
        },
        {
            "question": "I heard him …………………………. at the watchman.",
            "description": "Hear can be followed by an object + infinitive without to or object + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "shout",
                "shouting",
                "to shout"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fe10a93cadda48ff9b49b927a11bb024"
        },
        {
            "question": "I saw her ………………………….. into the pond.",
            "description": "The verb see can be followed by an object + infinitive or an object + ing form. The infinitive is used without to.",
            "answers": [
                "jump",
                "to jump",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c5443025c6e64bf695e09dae3d4023fc"
        },
        {
            "question": "I heard the bomb ………………………….",
            "description": "The ing form here suggests that we hear an action in progress whereas the infinitive suggests that we hear the whole of the action. When it comes to the sounds of explosions we are going to hear the whole of it and hence the infinitive is used here. ",
            "answers": [
                "explode",
                "to explode",
                "exploding"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "245a9f7170cd4c8c829c9999d8f4ec1b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I watched the kids …………………………… in the pond.",
            "description": "The ing form here suggests that we hear an action in progress whereas the infinitive suggests that we hear the whole of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "swim",
                "to swim",
                "swimming"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "401d16d8bd494c14a5ddc5aa36c703f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I could see him ……………………………. on the bus.",
            "description": "After can see or can hear only the –ing form is possible.",
            "answers": [
                "getting",
                "to get",
                "get"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f8bfa172b6234f218f3bdf66b1a55d74"
        },
        {
            "question": "I heard my name ……………………………… several times.",
            "description": "My name didn’t repeat. It was repeated. We use the past participle here to suggest this idea.",
            "answers": [
                "repeating",
                "repeat",
                "repeated"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5342b4d7240d44c9a5dd0e539dfb7560"
        },
        {
            "question": "Look at them …………………………..!",
            "description": "Look at can be followed by an infinitive or ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "dance",
                "dancing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "483edf49f5db419c98e5c285c9286ed4"
        }
    ]
}